Guide to the University of Chicago Office of the President, Kimpton Administration Records 1892-1960
University of Chicago Library
- Series I: General Files
  - Development, campaign, "To Meet a Responsibility," February 14, 1955 (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Development, campaign clippings, 1955-1956 (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Development, campaign organizational chart, January 12, 1955 (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Development, campaign publicity material, 1954-1956 (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - Development, campaign publicity material, 1954-1956 (Box 98, Folder 1-2)
  - Development, College, 1952-1960 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Development, Committee on, Board of Trustees, 1960 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Development, Committee on, John Price Jones Corporation, 1923-1959 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Development, corporations, 1959-1960 (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Development, Counseling Center, 1954 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - Development, Fact Book, 1955 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Development, Faculty Development Committee, Membership, 1957-1960 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Development, Faculty Development Committee, minutes, 1957-1960 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Development, Faculty Development Committee, newsletters, 1955-1959 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Development, Federated Theological Faculty, 1958-1960 (Box 99, Folder 5-6)
  - Development, foundation proposals, procedures for submission to foundations, 1960 (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Development, foundations, 1955-1959 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Development, fund-raising campaign, 1952-1958, information manuals (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Development, fund-raising campaign, alumni, Ludgin and McDonough letters, 1955-1956 (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Development, fund-raising campaign, corporations, 1952-1958 (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Development, Kersting, Brown & Company, fund-raising counsel, 1955-1959 (Box 100, Folder 5-6)
  - Development, Kersting, Brown & Company, "A Summary Report and Outline Plan," 1955 (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Development, Kersting, Brown & Company, "An Interim Report Covering the Period from the Initiation of the Campaign through June 30, 1956," by Robert F. Duncan, 1956 (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Development Office, 1950-1960 (Box 101, Folder 2-4)
  - Development Office, Divinity School, 1956-1960 (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Development Office, invitation list for the performance of "The Passion According to St. Matthew," March 9, 1953 (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Development Office, publications, "Genealogy of Greatness," 1955 (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Development, Office, publications, "Responsibility of Greatness," 1955-1956 (Box 101, Folder 8-9)
  - Development Office, special gifts prospects, 1957-1960 (Box 101, Folder 10)
  - Development Planning Conference, Washington University, University of Chicago, University of Pittsburgh, February 1957 (Box 101, Folder 11)
  - Development, Social Sciences, Divisional Committee, 1954 (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Development, South Campus, financing, proposals, 1959-1960 (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - D, general, 1955-1956 (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Disciples Divinity House, 1925-1960 (Box 102, Folder 4-6)
  - Dissertation Requirements, Committee on, Committee and Subcommittee on Theses, 1948-1952 (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Divinity School, 1951-1960 (Box 102, Folder 8-12)
  - Divinity School, new plan of cooperation, 1960 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - Divinity school, statistics, 1960 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Dormitories, invitations to officers to visit, 1957-1960 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Dormitories and residence halls, n.d. (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Dormitories and residence halls, general, 1951-1960 (Box 103, Folder 5-9)
  - Dormitories and residence halls, data, 1942-1954 (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - Dormitories and residence halls, Horwath and Horwath Survey of Feeding and Housing Operations, 1958 (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - Dormitories and residence halls, occupancy, 1940-1954 (Box 103, Folder 12)
  - Dormitories for Women, proposed building, 1928-1953 (Box 103, Folder 13)
  - Douglas, William O., 1936-1957 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Dream research, 1960 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Duncan, Hugh Dalziel, 1956-1957 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Earth Sciences, Committee on, 1954 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Eastern Association of College and University Business Officers, 1950-1960 (Box 104, Folder 5-7)
  - Economic Club of Chicago, 1955-1959 (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Economic Development Committee, 1957-1960 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Economics, Department of, 1951-1960 (Box 104, Folder 10-14)
  - Education, 1955 (Box 104, Folder 15)
  - Education, Department of, 1951-1960 (Box 105, Folder 1-7)
  - Education, Department of, annual reading conferences, 1957-1960 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Education, Department of, conferences, seminars, and workshops, 1954-1959 (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Education, Department and Graduate School of, discussions, proposals, and establishment, 1957-1958 (Box 106, Folder 1)
  - Education, Department and Graduate School of, faculty board, 1959 (Box 106, Folder 2)
  - Education, Department and Graduate School of, newsletter, 1956 (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - Education, Department and Graduate School of, Pakistan education project, 1957-1958 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Education, Department and Graduate School of, visiting committee, proposed, 1960 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Education, Graduate School of, 1956-1960 (Box 106, Folder 6-9)
  - Education, School of, Seminar on Higher Education in Latin America, December 15, 1959-March 15, 1960 (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - Education, School of, Conferences, Seminars and Workshops, 1952-1954 (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - Educational conference, 1955 (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - Educational Fund, 1943-1958 (Box 106, Folder 13)
  - Educational Fund, budget, finance, 1951-1957 (Box 106, Folder 14)
  - Educational Testing Service, 1955-1958 (Box 106, Folder 15)
  - Egyptian universities, 1950-1956 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Eisenhower, President Dwight D., 1955-1959 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Electronic Technical Institute, 1958 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Emeriti Census, 1957-1959 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Emeritus, appointments, 1947-1959 (Box 107, Folder 5-6)
  - Emery-Drexel livery, 1959-1960 (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - Emory University, 1955-1959 (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - Endowment funds, 1944-1958 (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - Endowment funds, comparative studies and articles, 1951-1960 (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - England, visit of Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Philip, July 6, 1959 (Box 107, Folder 11)
  - English, Department of, 1951-1960 (Box 107, Folder 12-15)
  - English, Department of, Craigie, William Alexander, 1928-1957 (Box 107, Folder 16)
  - English Language and Literature, Department of, chairmanship, 1960 (Box 107, Folder 17)
  - Entertaining, 1955 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Episcopal Church, 1952-1959 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Equipment, policies and procedures, 1953-1960 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - European-American Conference, 1958 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - European Community for Coal and Steel, 1956 (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Examinations, Board of, membership, 1945-1955 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Examinations, Committee on, membership, 1955 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Examinations, general, 1951-1955 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Examinations, schedules, 1951-1960 (Box 108, Folder 9-10)
  - Examiner, Office of, 1951-1957 (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - Examiner, Office of, space, 1949-1957 (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Exchange Visitor Program, P-100, 1949-1954 (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Executive Club of Chicago, 1951-1960 (Box 109, Folder 3-6)
  - Executive functions, 1955 (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Executive Program of the Business School, 1951-1960 (Box 109, Folder 8-10)
  - Executives in the Federal Government, Study of, jointly undertaken by Cornell University and the University of Chicago, 1958-1959 (Box 109, Folder 11)
  - Facts sheet, 1955 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Faculties, Secretary of, 1952-1960 (Box 110, Folder 2-3)
  - Faculty, 1956-1958 (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Committee, Mr. Wilson, 1955 (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Faculty, current, 1955 (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Development Committee, 1956-1960 (Box 110, Folder 7-8)
  - Faculty Exchange, 1953-1958 (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - Faculty, 4-E Contract, 1951-1959 (Box 110, Folder 10)
  - Faculty-Graduate Committee for Peace, 1950-1953 (Box 110, Folder 11)
  - Faculty, honors and memberships in national societies, 1954-1960 (Box 110, Folder 12)
  - Faculty Housing Project, files of J. Parker Hall, 1944-1952 (Box 110, Folder 13-14)
  - Faculty Housing Project, files of J. Parker Hall, 1944-1952 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Faculty-Industry Committee of the School of Business, 1948-1952 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Faculty newcomers program, 1957-1960 (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Faculty News Bulletin, 1943-1960 (Box 111, Folder 4-5)
  - Faculty teaching loads, 1957 (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Faculty wives dinners, 1957-1959 (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - Fairweather, George O., 1929-1956 (Box 111, Folder 8)
  - Far Eastern Association, Incorporated, 1952-1956 (Box 111, Folder 9)
  - Far Eastern Civilization, Committee on, 1951-1954 (Box 111, Folder 10)
  - Far Eastern Studies, Committee on, 1951-1960 (Box 111, Folder 11)
  - Federal Aid to Education, 1958 (Box 111, Folder 12)
  - Federal Aid to Education, general, 1957-1959 (Box 111, Folder 13)
  - Federal City Council, 1958-1960 (Box 112, Folder 1-5)
  - Federal Tax Conference, 1952-1960 (Box 112, Folder 6-7)
  - Federated Theological Faculty, 1955-1960 (Box 112, Folder 8-9)
  - Federated Theological Faculty, 1956-1960 (Box 113, Folder 1-3)
  - Federated Theological Faculty, Board of, 1945-1960 (Box 113, Folder 4-9)
  - Federated Theological Faculty, a brief history, 1946-1960 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Federated Theological Faculty, deanship, 1953-1960 (Box 114, Folder 2-4)
  - Federated Theological Faculty, inauguration of dean, 1955 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Federated Theological Faculty, Inter-Board Committee on Academic Affairs, 1954-1960 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Federated Theological Faculty, internal organization changes, 1943-1953 (Box 115, Folder 2-3)
  - Federated Theological Faculty, luncheon honoring Jaroslav Pelikan, 1959 (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - Federated Theological Faculty, negotiations, 1959-1960 (Box 115, Folder 5-8)
  - Federated Theological Faculty, negotiations, May-June 1960 (Box 116, Folder 1-2)
  - Federated Theological Faculty, negotiations and termination, July-September 1960 (Box 116, Folder 3-4)
  - Federated Theological Faculty, "Religion Faces the Atomic Age" Conference, February 2-3, 1958 (Box 116, Folder 6-7)
  - Federation of Illinois Colleges, 1951-1959 (Box 116, Folder 8-9)
  - Federation of Illinois Colleges, annual meeting materials, 1957-1960 (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Fees, 1951-1960 (Box 117, Folder 2-5)
  - Fees, actual income, 1952-1955 (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Fees, other schools, 1953-1960 (Box 117, Folder 7-8)
  - Feldstein, Charles R. and Company, Inc., agreements and contracts, 1955-1960 (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships, Committee on, 1954-1955 (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Fermi, Enrico, Institute, directorship, 1954-1960 (Box 117, Folder 11)
  - Fermi, Enrico, Institute for Nuclear Studies, Proposal to U.S. Atomic Energy Commission for Elementary Particle Physics Laboratory, 1959 (Box 117, Folder 12)
  - Fermi, Enrico, publication of Notes on Quantum Mechanics, 1960 (Box 117, Folder 13)
  - Fermi, Laura, Atoms in the Family, 1954 (Box 117, Folder 14)
  - Festival of the Arts, FOTA, first, 1955 (Box 117, Folder 15)
  - Festival of the Arts, FOTA, 1955-1960 (Box 118, Folder 1-6)
  - F, general, 1955-1956 (Box 118, Folder 7)
  - Filing procedures, procedures and subject headings, 1956-1957 (Box 118, Folder 8)
  - Filing procedures, file index, general, 1956-1957 (Box 118, Folder 9)
  - Filing procedures, file index, University of Chicago, 1956-1957 (Box 118, Folder 10-12)
  - Financial policy and program, 1954-1958 (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Fine Arts Center, proposed, 1960 (Box 119, Folder 2)
  - Fiscal year, possible change, 1959-1960 (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - Flexner, Abraham, 1925-1960 (Box 119, Folder 4)
  - Florence Agreement, National Committee for, 1959-1960 (Box 119, Folder 5)
  - Florida State University, 1949-1960 (Box 119, Folder 6)
  - Food Research Institute, 1949-1959 (Box 119, Folder 7-9)
  - Food Research Institute, brochures and proposals, 1940-1958 (Box 119, Folder 10-11)
  - Food Research Institute, food industry proposal for support of, 1952-1960 (Box 119, Folder 12)
  - Food Research Institute, Quartermaster Food and Container Institute, 1955-1960 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Food Research Institute, Staphylococcus Food Poisoning Project, 1946-1959 (Box 120, Folder 2)
  - Food service, Hutchinson Commons, 1958 (Box 120, Folder 3)
  - Football, clippings and articles, 1943-1954 (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Football, Committee on Student Recreational Activities, 1955-1956 (Box 120, Folder 5)
  - Football, general, 1945-1960 (Box 120, Folder 6-8)
  - Football, letters about, 1951-1954 (Box 120, Folder 9)
  - Football, meeting of universities, 1951-1955 (Box 120, Folder 10)
  - Ford Foundation, New Yorker profile, 1955 (Box 120, Folder 11)
  - Foreign students, general, 1944-1959 (Box 120, Folder 12)
  - Fortune magazine, 1955-1957 (Box 120, Folder 13)
  - Foundation plan, 1954 (Box 120, Folder 14)
  - Foundations, 1955-1956 (Box 120, Folder 15)
  - Four-E contracts, 1943-1955 (Box 120, Folder 16-18)
  - Four-E contracts, outside earnings of faculty, policies, practices, and procedures, 1949-1957 (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Four-e contracts, salaries and related statistics, 1951-1956 (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Foreign language requirements for higher degrees, committee on, 1954-1956 (Box 121, Folder 3)
  - Franck, James, institute for the study of metals, 1951-1960 (Box 121, Folder 4)
  - Frankfurt-Chicago Inter-University Project, 1950-1959 (Box 121, Folder 5-7)
  - Frankfurt-Chicago Inter-University Project, Advisory Committee, 948-1960 (Box 121, Folder 8)
  - Frankfurt-Chicago Inter-University Project, agriculture utilization of resources, 1952 (Box 121, Folder 9-10)
  - Frankfurt-Chicago Inter-University Project, space, 1954 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Fraternities, 1956-1960 (Box 122, Folder 2-4)
  - Fraternities, Committee on, 1958-1959 (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - Fraternities, Gamma Alpha and Phi Delta Theta, 1958-1960 (Box 122, Folder 6)
  - Fraternities, "Michigan Plan," 1954 (discrimination) (Box 122, Folder 7)
  - Fraternities, university policy, 1951-1954 (Box 122, Folder 8)
  - Fraternities and sororities at the university, interfraternity council, 1951-1960 (Box 122, Folder 9)
  - Fraternities and sororities at the university, Tau Kappa Epsilon, 1954 (Box 122, Folder 10)
  - French Exchange Fellowships and Professorships, 1948-1954 (Box 122, Folder 11)
  - Fried, Bernard Allen, 1952 (Box 122, Folder 12)
  - Frost, Edwin Brant, 1930-1955 (Box 122, Folder 13)
  - Fulbright Act, 1947-1952 (Box 122, Folder 14)
  - Funds, restricted expendable, statements, 1952-1958 (Box 122, Folder 15)
  - Funds, reserve and suspense, statements, 1951-1960 (Box 122, Folder 16)
  - Funds, general, 1957-1960 (Box 122, Folder 17)
  - Furrow, Grace O., alumna, 1955 (Box 122, Folder 18)
  - Future of the University, Committee on the, 1960 (Box 122, Folder 19)
  - Gary, Indiana, 1956-1958 (Box 122, Folder 20)
  - General Nuclear Engineering Corporation, 1959 (Box 122, Folder 21)
  - General Studies, Institute of, 1953 (Box 122, Folder 22)
  - General Studies in the Humanities, Committee on, 1951-1955 (Box 122, Folder 23)
  - Geography, Department of, 1950-1959 (Box 122, Folder 24-27)
  - Geology, Department of, 1950-1960 (Box 123, Folder 1-2)
  - Geology, Department of, space, 1958 (Box 123, Folder 3)
  - Geophysics, Institute of, proposed, 1957 (Box 123, Folder 4)
  - George Williams College, 1944-1957 (Box 123, Folder 5)
  - German, Germany, 1955-1960 (Box 123, Folder 6)
  - Germanic Languages and Literatures, Department of, 1952-1960 (Box 123, Folder 7-8)
  - Germany, Federal Republic of, visit of President Theodor Heuss, June 1958 (Box 123, Folder 9)
  - G, general, 1950-1956 (Box 123, Folder 10-11)
  - Gift acknowledgment procedure, 1960 (Box 123, Folder 12)
  - Gift opportunities, 1955-1956 (Box 123, Folder 13)
  - Gift pledges, reminders, payments, 1957-1960 (Box 123, Folder 14)
  - Gift procedure, trustee giving, 1956-1960 (Box 123, Folder 15)
  - Gift programs of companies, matching, 1955-1960 (Box 123, Folder 16)
  - Gift reports, 1955-1956 (Box 123, Folder 17)
  - Gift routine, 1952-1957 (Box 123, Folder 18)
  - Gift routine, procedure used for campaign, 1954-1956 (Box 123, Folder 19)
  - Gift of securities, 1955 (Box 123, Folder 20)
  - Gifts, campaign progress reports, 1957-1958 (Box 123, Folder 21)
  - Gifts, comparative reports, 1946-1959 (Box 123, Folder 22)
  - Gifts for E.C. Colwell Fund, Committee on, 1951 (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - Gifts, general, 1955-1960 (Box 124, Folder 2-3)
  - Gifts of objects, 1959-1960 (Box 124, Folder 4)
  - Gifts of real property to the U of C, 1954-1960 (Box 124, Folder 5)
  - Gifts, subscription forms, acknowledgement of, 1955 (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - Gifts, Zinzow report, 1954 (Box 124, Folder 7)
  - Ginzberg, Eli, 1937-1955 (Box 124, Folder 8)
  - Goucher College, 1960 (Box 124, Folder 9)
  - Government contracts, 1943-1958 (Box 124, Folder 10-12)
  - Government contracts, 1955-1960 (Box 125, Folder 1-5)
  - Government contracts, United States Armed Forces Institute, 1953-1960 (Box 125, Folder 6)
  - Grades, grading, 1958-1960 (Box 125, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Departments, Bernard Berelson, "Graduate Education in the United States," 1960 (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - Graduate Departments, ratings of, Keniston Survey, 1957 (Box 126, Folder 2)
  - Graduate education in the U.S., study of, Bernard Berelson, 1957-1960 (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Record Examination Board, 1943-1956 (Box 126, Folder 4)
  - Graduate study, statistics, 1949-1960 (Box 126, Folder 5-6)
  - Great Books Foundation, 1947-1960 (Box 127, Folder 1-3)
  - Great Books Foundation, board, 1955 (Box 127, Folder 4)
  - Great Books Foundation, gifts to the, 1947-1959 (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Great Books of the Western World, 1943-1959 (Box 127, Folder 6-7)
  - Great Books Program, National Survey Report #68, 1958 (Box 127, Folder 8)
  - Greece, H.M. Frederika and H.R.H. Princess Sophia, visit to University campus and Argonne National Laboratory, November 5, 1958 (Box 127, Folder 9)
  - Hamilton, Alexander, 1952-1957 (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - Harding, George Franklin, museum, university interests, 1955-1960 (Box 128, Folder 2)
  - Harrell, William B., speech file, 1955-1957 (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - Harris, Norman Wait, Foundation, Institution, 1950-1954 (Box 128, Folder 4)
  - Harris, Norman Wait, Memorial Foundation, 1954-1957 (Box 128, Folder 5)
  - Harrison, R. Wendell, letters of congratulation on appointment to acting chancellorship, 1960 (Box 128, Folder 6)
  - Harvard Law School, "Role of International Law and International Institutions as Conflict Adjusting Agencies," L.B. Sohn, 1960 (Box 128, Folder 7)
  - Harvard University, 1951-1960 (Box 128, Folder 8-10)
  - Harvard University, Divinity School, 1953 (Box 128, Folder 11)
  - Harvard University, President's Reports, 1951-1958 (Box 128, Folder 12)
  - Health Information Foundation, negotiations and affiliation, 1956 (Box 128, Folder 13)
  - Health Service, Student, 1950-1960 (Box 128, Folder 14-16)
  - Health services, reports, 1955-1958 (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - Herold, Thomas Edward, 1959 (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - History, Department of, 1951-1960 (Box 129, Folder 3-7)
  - History, Department of, chairmanship, 1957 (Box 129, Folder 8)
  - History, Department of, faculty, Daniel J. Boorstin, "Role of Ideas in American Culture," 1954-1957 (Box 129, Folder 9)
  - History, Department of, W.T. Hutchinson's "The Department of History in Retrospect," April 16, 1956 (Box 129, Folder 10)
  - History of Colleges and Universities, 1955 (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - History of the University, quotations, 1951-1955 (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - History of the University of Chicago, I, selection of historian and archivist, excerpts, 1886-1957 (Box 130, Folder 3-4)
  - History of the University of Chicago, II, selection of historian and archivist, excerpts, 1897-1952 (Box 130, Folder 5-6)
  - History of the University of Chicago, III, selection of historian and archivist, excerpts, 1953-1956 (Box 130, Folder 7-8)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, Devise, 1955-1960 (Box 130, Folder 9)
  - Home for Destitute and Crippled Children, 1960 (Box 130, Folder 10)
  - Home for Destitute and Crippled Children, affiliation agreements and negotiations, 1959-1960 (Box 130, Folder 11)
  - Home for Destitute and Crippled children, staff appointment recommendations, 1955-1960 (Box 130, Folder 12)
  - Home for Destitute and Crippled Children, staff appointments, 1950-1954 (Box 130, Folder 13)
  - Home Economics, Committee on, 1950-1956 (Box 131, Folder 1)
  - Home Economics, Committee on Termination of, September 30, 1956 (Box 131, Folder 2)
  - Home Economics, Committee on, termination, 1948-1958 (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - Home Economics, Department of, committees, 1948-1958 (Box 131, Folder 4)
  - Home Study, Department of, 1951-1960 (Box 131, Folder 5-10)
  - Home Study, Department of, 1955-1960 (Box 132, Folder 1)
  - Home Study, Department of, space, 1956-1959 (Box 132, Folder 2)
  - Home Study, Department of, TV lectures, 1955-1957 (Box 132, Folder 3)
  - Homecoming, 1953 (Box 132, Folder 4)
  - Honorary degrees, 1951 (Box 132, Folder 5)
  - Honorary Degrees, Committee on, 1946-1960 (Box 132, Folder 6-8)
  - Honorary Degrees, Committee on, membership, 1945-1960 (Box 132, Folder 9-10)
  - Honorary Degrees, Committee on, suggested candidates, 1951-1960 (Box 132, Folder 11-12)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Laird Bell, May 8, 1953 (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Henry Stanley Bennett, June 19, 1955 (Box 133, Folder 2)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Gaston Berger, December 12, 1953 (Box 133, Folder 3)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Hans Albrecht Bethe, June 12, 1953 (Box 133, Folder 4)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Hugo L. Black, March 19, 1954 (Box 133, Folder 5)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Arthur Frank Burns, September 2, 1960 (Box 133, Folder 6)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Zechariah Chafee, Jr., December 8, 1953 (Box 133, Folder 7)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Arthur Holly Compton, December 19, 1952 (Box 133, Folder 8)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, George Washington Corner, June 13, 1958 (Box 133, Folder 9)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Edward Charles Dodds, June 12, 1959 (Box 133, Folder 10)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Nicholson Joseph Eastmen, June 13, 1958 (Box 133, Folder 11)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Emery Thomas Filbey, September 2, 1955 (Box 133, Folder 12)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Ronald Ayler Fisher, June 13, 1952 (Box 133, Folder 13)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Felix Frankfurter, May 8, 1953 (Box 133, Folder 14)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Frederick C. Grant, August 28, 1953 (Box 133, Folder 15)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, William Haller, June 8, 1956 (Box 133, Folder 16)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Learned Hand, December 19, 1952 (Box 133, Folder 17)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Hans Adolf Krebs, March 19, 1954 (Box 134, Folder 1)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Hans Kurath, December 18, 1959 (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Fritz Albert Lipman, June 12, 1953 (Box 134, Folder 3)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Andre Michel Lwoff, March 20, 1959 (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Kemp Malone, June 12, 1953 (Box 134, Folder 5)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Jerzy Neyman, June 12, 1959 (Box 134, Folder 6)
  - Honorary Degrees, recipients of, Niebuhr, H. Richard, August 24, 1954 (Box 134, Folder 7)